NordicTrack is one of the most popular
companies in the cardio space with their
extensive line of treadmills so
naturally we ordered the most sought
after models and tested them ourselves
so after reviewing their treadmills the
three main reasons why I think
NordicTrack is so popular within the
cardio space is because of the money the
streaming capabilities and the overall
versatility so if we talk about
streaming first overall experience even
the visuals is just as good if not
better than what you're going to get
from adjacent companies like Peloton now
with versatility they've invested a lot
of time and effort into iFit so don't
know what iFit is it's a massive catalog
of online workout classes you can just
stream whatever you want and this has
allowed them to really expand their
capabilities their opportunities I guess
you could say far beyond just cardio and
running so whether you want to do some
strength training some yoyo some
meditation hit workouts really whatever
it is you can stream all that directly
from these monitors so the treadmill
almost serves as if if it's an actual
full home gym and then if we talk about
money you know there's plenty of options
based on your budget whether you want to
keep it somewhat basic and go after
their cheapest model or you want the
features to be just as high as that
price tag and go after you know the head
honcho there's going to be an option for
you and that's what I think is another
thing is so great they're gonna there's
gonna be a specific option that meets
your specific needs the best so in this
video today we're going to talk about
that I'm going to talk about what I
think is the best you know overall
General Runner what's the best for those
on a budget and which one is the best
for those intense training sessions and
a whole lot more
[Music]
all right we got a long video today and
I don't want to waste any of your time
so why don't I just go ahead and kind of
spill the beans and tell you which
treadmill I personally think is the best
overall option the one that I think
literally anybody could buy and be happy
with it right out of the box
it's the NordicTrack commercial 1750. I
mean honestly the 1750 just checks off
all the boxes for me it's really
versatile it's high-tech and honestly in
terms of money it's right down the
middle compared to you know some other
competing Brands now I'm going to expand
on the 1750 in just a second and talk
about you know why I think it's the best
overall option but I'm also going to be
talking about you know a handful of
other treadmills today as well but
before I do all that I gotta let you
know we've reviewed dozens and dozens of
other treadmills on barbin.com and we
went ahead and made a best list of all
of our top choices that of course
feature NordicTrack but also many other
brands as well so if you want to check
that out all you got to do is search bar
Ben best treadmills it's going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourselves which ones we like the best
okay so I just told you the commercial
1750 is my choice for the top overall
Nordic Track treadmill but let's expand
on why I think that's true so all these
treadmills have the same similar modern
conveniences but when it comes to having
that perfect balance of features and
affordability 1750 just gets it done so
it has a max incline of 12 which isn't
you know out of the ordinary but it does
have a minus three percent decline which
is you know a bit of a rarity it also
has a 3.5 CHP motor which CHP stands for
constant horsepower so you know a lot of
times with other you know lower end
treadmills they just have HP so HP just
kind of referring to that Peak
Performance Peak horsepower CHP you know
it's always going to be performing at
that you know highest capacity now in
addition to the automatic adjustments
through iFit it's going to adjust the
incline decline in speed settings you
can also also use the active pulse
technology of this treadmill and so
basically what you got to do is you got
to purchase the NordicTrack heart rate
monitor and then you pair it up with
your treadmill and basically you know
it's going to read your heart rate and
then adjust your difficulty to keep your
heart rate in the optimal Zone which is
also pretty cool and speaking of iFit
remember there's a massive catalog of
classes that you can stream directly you
know from your fingertips but the cool
thing about this specific model is that
that 14 inch touchscreen monitor can
rotate it can tilt for your neck and you
know for viewing whenever you're on the
treadmill but also you can hop off the
treadmill rotate it 360 and do those
additional classes from the floor
treadmill is also going to run you right
around 2500 bucks which considering all
the features that you're getting from it
I think it's more than worthy of that
price tag the only thing here is that I
wish the rollers were bigger than 1.9
inches so rollers are directly
responsible for allowing the belt to
turn and the thicker the diameter is the
less they have to wear work and the
longer they're going to last Honestly
though 1.9 still gonna get the job done
for most people it may be just not you
know hardcore long distance Runners and
also it's kind of a common theme with
nordictracks treadmills
so there it is my friends our Top Choice
right off the bat it's the commercial
1750 I mean when it really comes down to
the features and the approachable price
tag it just simply Takes the Cake here
[Music]
all right so I just mentioned the 1750
has an approachable price tag but if
you're looking for the best budget
friendly option we had to give the nod
to the EXP 7i it has pretty much all the
same luxury features these other models
have but just you know at a smaller
scale so for example the actual deck
itself measures 55 inches long by 20
inches wide as opposed to 60 inches long
and 22 inches wide instead of a 12
incline you have a 10 incline and
there's no decline settings and the top
speed is 10 miles per hour now it has a
2.6 CHP motor which is the weakest out
of all of these treadmills but it's also
the cheapest like I said it's best for
the budget it's going to run you right
around thirteen hundred dollars now yes
there are plenty of other treadmills on
the market that are in this same price
range but those aren't going to have the
same features and luxury features
specifically as you're going to get
right here with the EXP 7i now we also
chose the EXP 7i to beat our best
treadmill for NordicTrack for walking
now typically with treadmills you know
I'd kind of Base this off of the size of
the rollers but since the majority of
them are 1.9 inches in diameter I think
it really just boils down for me at
least to the actual strength of the
motor remember it's 2.6 CHP so it's the
weakest on this list now you can still
run remember you got that 10 mile per
hour you know top speed but really at
the end of the day you know this motor
isn't going to be strong enough to you
know have some long distance running so
that's where it really just kind of
boils in to you know walking
specifically and then don't forget you
do have that 12 incline so you can
really make your walk as difficult as
possible all right so there it is exp 7i
best for the money remember it's about
1300 bucks and best for walking remember
it has the same luxury features as all
these other models just at a smaller
scale including that seven inch
touchscreen monitor
hahaha
[Music]
okay so we just talked about you know
best for walking now let's transition a
little bit and talk about the best
Nordictrack treadmill for running and I
think for this one we had to go with the
2450 the 3.6 CHP motor is going to allow
it to run for an extended period of time
that was really no pun intended I
promise it's gonna allow it to run for
an extended period of time at high
speeds and you know a lot of the specs
are nearly identical to the 1750 but
since these treadmills you know are
designed to be used in tandem with iFit
the main reason here for me at least is
the 22 inch touchscreen monitor you know
it's going to be more immersive
throughout those classes whether you're
you know like I said streaming a class
from iFit or you're using you know
Google Maps I love the Google Maps
features on these treadmills it's going
to give you that Google you know Street
camera view as you're running through
whatever City you want and I just think
that really just kind of makes it you
know go over the top a little bit right
here compared to the other treadmills
you also have the active pulse
technology here with the 2450 so if you
get that Nordic Track heart rate monitor
number it's gonna you know adjust the
difficulty of your workouts to keep your
heart rate in the optimal Zone and
remember you do have a Max incline of 12
a Max decline of three percent so that's
going to allow you to your sprinkle in
some Hill work if you're somebody who
likes to run on Hills
foreign
okay so what about those people who like
to walk or run on a really steep incline
well if that's you then look no further
than the commercial x-22i which as you
guessed it is our Top Choice for the
best NordicTrack Incline treadmill this
Beast of a treadmill weighs a hefty 417
pounds and it doesn't fold so it's not
going to be the best for anybody you
know working with some tight space but
in addition to the industry-leading 40
incline it also has a negative six
degree Decline and it has a top speed of
12 miles per hour but what really is
probably my favorite thing about this
treadmill is the super unique sled push
so basically what you're going to be
doing is you know putting the treadmill
on one mile per hour and then just
grabbing onto the handlebars that are up
top and then just driving your legs and
pushing it just as you would push a sled
and that's going to be really great for
anybody who wants to strengthen their
posterior chain you also have 2.5 inch
rollers a 22 inch touchscreen monitor
and a 4.0 CHP motor to also pair along
with reflex cushioning which is
basically just going to respond to your
body weight and make sure you have
optimal cushioning at all times
throughout your workouts so honestly you
might even be able to make the case that
this is the most versatile treadmill
that NordicTrack has to offer so if you
are in fact looking for the steepest
incline available and you have the
budget for 3 500 treadmill the x22i is
definitely calling your names foreign
[Music]
majority of the treadmills on this list
do in fact fold we rank the commercial
1250 as the best folding option from
NordicTrack and the main reason for this
is because it's beefier than the EXP 7i
and it's a little bit cheaper than the
1750s so you have a 10 inch touchscreen
monitor that will tilt and rotate so you
can do those additional classes from the
ground it has a 12 incline a minus three
percent Decline and a top speed of 12
miles per hour to go along with the 3.0
CHP motor and similar to the other
models the 1250 you know does in fact
have a hydraulic lift system that really
just takes all the effort of folding and
unfolding the deck out of the equation
it's super easy you can do it with one
hand and that's just going to really
allow you to make the most of your
available space
[Music]
foreign
okay so I just want to take a second and
kind of talk about you know how we chose
these treadmills for you know this list
but also you know which one you should
Target and you know for this we decided
to factor in the things that we consider
to be you know the most important
factors that most people are tending to
look after so speed and incline range
that's available the actual size of the
monitors and then of course the money
you know just because the x32i is the
most expensive treadmill that they offer
doesn't necessarily mean that it's the
best available and doesn't mean it's the
best for you specifically so that's why
we made this video you know very
specific the x22i is nearly identical to
the x32i but it's about 900 cheaper the
1750 has just about everything you could
ask for you know making it the best
all-around option the 2450 is going to
be best suited for those who strictly
want to run especially because of that
immersive 22 inch touchscreen monitor
exp 7i is perfect for my friends who are
Balling on a budget and then the 1250
you know is Just A step above the EXP 7i
but it still has that folding deck which
is perfect for so many different reasons
so when it really comes down to you know
finding the best treadmill for you
specifically I don't really think you
can go wrong with any of these
treadmills I just think you need to
align your goals and your budget and
then you're easily going to find the one
that's best for you
foreign
[Music]
that's a wrap on today's review over
what we believe to be the best
treadmills available from NordicTrack as
I just mentioned I don't think you can
go wrong with any of them but there is
bound to be one model here that is best
for your specific needs thanks for
hanging out with me Fam I hope you found
this video to be really helpful and I
was able to break down everything you
need to know about these treadmills as
always stay posted for my next video but
for now I gotta let you guys know we
have a full written article that pairs
with this video and I think you will
find it really helpful so if you want to
check that out all you got to do is
search barvin best NordicTrack
treadmills it's going to pull right up
for you you can go over everything we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
[Music]
thank you